---
0:
  question: "Which one of these is not a primitive data type?"
  options:
    - "Integer"
    - "Char"
    - "String"
  answer: 2
1:
  question: "Java source code is stored in files with what extension?"
  options:
    - ".class"
    - ".java"
    - ".jav"
  answer: 1
2:
  question: "The best environment for developing Java applications is?"
  options:
    - "A UNIX server hosted by a corporate entity"
    - "Eclipse IDE"
    - "Whatever you are most comfortable in"
  answer: 2
3:
  question: "Java can be used to write?"
  options:
    - "Web applications"
    - "Desktop programs"
    - "all of the above"
  answer: 2
4:
  question: "which GUI toolkit comes included with Java?"
  options:
    - "Swing"
    - "Gtk"
    - "JavaFX"
  answer: 0
5:
  question: "the current version of Java is?"
  options:
    - "8"
    - "1.8"
    - "This is a trick question (aka both)"
  answer: 2
6:
  question: "Java is a?"
  options:
    - "Byte-code compiled language"
    - "Interpreted language"
    - "Compiled language"
  answer: 0
7:
  question: "The file extension for MyApp.java after running javac MyApp.java"
  options:
    - ".exe"
    - ".class"
    - ".java"
  answer: 1
8:
  question: "In Java console output i achieved by using?"
  options:
    - "sted::cout"
    - "printf"
    - "System.out.println"
  answer: 2
9:
  question: "Java applications are executes in?"
  options:
    - "An interpreter"
    - "A virtual machine"
    - "On your computer"
  answer: 1
10:
  question: "How many times will the following code print Welcome to Java\n int count=0;\n while (count < 10) {\n System.out.println(Welcome to Java)}"
  options:
    - "9"
    - "10"
    - "11"
  answer: 1
11:
  question: "An object is an instance of a _______"
  options:
    - "Program"
    - "Class"
    - "Method"
  answer: 1
12:
  Question: "Variables that are shared by every instances of a class are"
  options:
    - "public variables"
    - "instance variables"
    - "class variables"
  answer: 2
13:
  question: "The less than or equal to comparison operator in Java is"
  options:
    - "<="
    - "=<"
    - "!="
  answer: 0
14:
  question: "In Java the word true is"
  options:
    - "A Java keyword"
    - "A Boolean literal"
    - "Same as value 1"
  answer: 1
15:
  question: "What is the representation of the third element in an array called a?"
  options:
    - "a[2]"
    - "a(2)"
    - "a[3]"
  answer: 0
16:
  question: "Which of the following statements will convert a string s into a double value d?"
  options:
    - "d = Double.parseDouble(s);"
    - "d = Double.valueOf(s).doubleValue();"
    - "both of the above"
  answer: 2
17:
  question: "How many elements are array matrix (int[][] matrix = new int[5][5])?"
  options:
    - "20"
    - "25"
    - "30"
  answer: 1
18:
  question: "What is Math.round(3.6)?"
  options:
    - "4.0"
    - "4"
    - "3.0"
  answer: 1
19:
  question: "A Java character is stored in _____."
  options:
    - "one byte"
    - "two bytes"
    - "four bytes"
  answer: 1

